# Kyle S. Greene

www.github.com/kylegreene

kgreene06@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/kylesheagreene/

13705 Lynn St, Apt #2 Woodbridge, VA 22191 347.424.3642

#### **Summary:**

Experienced software engineer with a passion for creating and maintaining fascinating web applications. Problem solver who has domain knowledge in finance. Knowledgeable of all phases of application development using AGILE methodologies and Test Driven Development. Well versed in Javascript, Java, MySQL and frameworks. Expert at working in a team setting and leadership.

## **Professional Experience:**

Capital One Tysons Corner, VA 2/2019- Present

- Migrated our current AngularJS application to Angular 7
- Leveraged AWS resources to use a serverless architecture with the new Angular 7 application
- Implemented different solutions to ensure our API's were always tuned for optimal performance
- Refactored code to be compliant with accessibility standards
- Used unit and end to end testing to ensure that our front end application was performant
- Acted as a resource for my team in understanding Angular along with front end development

TekSystems- Ford Motor Credit Company

Dearborn, MI

9/2018-2/2019

- Lead the change from vanilla CSS to Bootstrap 4 in our front end codebase
- Designed and implemented a new microservice to gather information about customers driving tendencies
- Owned the process of writing end to end tests along with unit tests for our client side application
- Helped migrate from version 1 of Pivotal Cloud Foundry to version 2
- Implemented different Google fonts on our client side application to improve readability
- Refactored our server side codebase to help facilitate better writing of unit and integration tests

9/2017 - 8/2018 Q-up, LLC(Quicken Loans) Detroit, MI

- Established new features into our core application such as change user and change password for overall user experience improvement.
- Engineered a credit score simulation endpoint using Transunion's API and integrated into our native application's API.
- Improved our codebase for our RESTful API in Java to facilitate faster response times.
- Added custom styling to base application using SASS.
- Constructed and implemented the administrative panel for an internal tool from a design.
- Optimized features in our administrative panel to reduce the number of engagement by 60%

# **Education:**

**B.S in Applied Mathematics Oakland University** 2005 M.Ed in Educational Leadership **Tennessee State University** 2011

### **Technical Skills:**

Scripting & Languages: Java, Object Oriented JavaScript (ES5/ES6), HTML5, CSS2/3, Python

Frameworks/Libraries: Angular, ReactJS, Redux, React Native, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap, Spring Boot, SASS, jQuery

Database: MySQL

Unit Testing & Automation: Protractor, Jasmine, Karma, Selenium, Jest, Cypress

Build & CLI Tools: Grunt, Gulp, NPM, NVM, Bower

Source Control: Git, GitHub

Other: Jenkins, JIRA, Confluence, Amazon Web Services, Docker